Stephen Merth

Javascript developer working with React/React Native, Gatsby, Apollo, GraphQL, Express and Cloud Functions to build serverless applications.

To contribute my development skills and management experience to a colleagues/users/customers to build cutting edge cloud based applications.

+1 604 446 4317

stephen.merth@gmail.com

smerth

in smerth

StephenMerth

SKILLS

Cross Functional Team

Management Experienced

Account

Management experienced

Business Development

Expert

LANGUAGES

English

Mandarin Chinese

Native speaker

Beginner / Conversational

AWARDS

Certificate of Appreciation

IMR (Medical Research Institute) & Malaysian Immunology Association

For organizing and conducting the workshop: 'Innovations in Proteomic Techniques - Protein Analysis in the 21st Century

North American Salesperson of the Year

Pharmacia Riotech Inc.

Best sales results in North America versus budget and growth year-on-year.

Presidents Award

Pharmacia Biotech Inc.

Global recognition for sales performance and upholding company values.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Elections Canada Deputy Returning Officer

(October 2019 - October 2019)

Ran polling station

City of Maple Ridge

(October 2018 - October 2018)

Election Officer

Ran polling station

Hauxsamaly Pte. Ltd. Founder / Managing Director

(June 2010 - December 2014)

I built, installed and maintained **Drupal** CMS instances for startup businesses, helping connect them with their customers and audiences

Bio-Works Company Ltd.

Commercial Director / Euity Stakeholder

(January 2013 - January 2014)

I joined Bio-works, a start-up protein separations technology company, in its first year of operation as employee #1. I worked with the 4 founders on all areas of business development and raising capital.

General Electric - Healthcare Division

(January 2005 - January 2007)

(January 2000 - November

2002)

Sales Support Director, Industrial Protein Separations, Developing Markets and Japan

Responsible for sales support functions for the Industrial Separations Business Group covering Asia Pacific, Africa, Middle East, Eastern Europe and South America.

Amersham Biosciences Ltd.

Regional Business Director, Drug Discovery Systems, Proteomics, Genomics -Asia Pacific

Ensured integration of product sales, marketing & support after aquisition of Molcular Dynamics. Focused business profit pivoting towards constant revenue stream and high margins of consumable chemistry.

Pharmacia Biotech Inc.

(July 1997 - January 2000)

Regional Marketing Manager - Asia Pacific

Coordinated sales and marketing activities for , Molecular Biology and Electrophoresis the electrophoresis, cell biology, molecular biology, spectrophotometry, and agency product portfolios in the Asia Pacific region. Negotiated record 1.7 M USD technology transfer agreement with PORIM, Malaysia.

Pharmacia Biotech Inc.

(July 1997 - January 2000)

Territory Manager - Western Canada

Managed sales, installation, support and training for Molecular Biology & Protein Chromatography product categories in Western Canada. Consistently expanded market share and exceeded sales quotas (achieving: 1993: 108%, 1994: 129%, 1995: 135%, 1996: 110%.)

British Columbia Cancer Research Center

Research Technician (T4)

(April 1987 - December 1989)

Set up a research project, purchased equipment and supplies, and conducted studies of integrin distribution on the surface of peripheral blood mononuclear cells in response to cell culture conditions.

EDUCATION

University of British Columbia

(September 1982 - May 1986)

Bachelor of Science Biochemistry & Genetics